Before we get started with the dialogue let's just set the scene.
在我们开始对话之前，让我们先设置一下场景。
That means describe basically what's happening and talk about the roles or the characters involved with
这意味着基本上描述正在发生的事情并谈论所涉及的角色或角色
this little story.
这个小故事。
So one person let's call him Mr. Vincent
所以一个人让我们称他为文森特先生
and his first name will be David is taking a business trip to New York to visit the company where another
他的名字将是大卫正在纽约出差访问另一家公司
person works the other person's name.
人以他人的名义工作。
The person who lives in New York and works at that company is Luke same person.
住在纽约并在那家公司工作的人是卢克同一个人。
Maybe could be me maybe not.
也许可能是我也许不是。
And David Vincent or Mr. Vincent has a wife and she's coming along now she is not on a business trip
大卫文森特或文森特先生有一个妻子，她现在要来了，她不是出差
but she wants to come to New York.
但她想来纽约。
She's coming with him.
她要和他一起来。
She can maybe hang out go shopping or do whatever she wants.
她也许可以出去逛街或做任何她想做的事。
And her name is Lydia why.
她的名字叫莉迪亚为什么。
OK so Mr. Vincent or David Vincent is visiting the company where Luke works on business for whatever
好的，文森特先生或大卫文森特先生正在访问卢克从事业务的公司
reason.
原因。
And Lydia is his wife.
莉迪亚是他的妻子。
She's coming along.
她来了。
She's going to accompany him.
她要陪他。
OK.
好的。
And Luke lives in New York.
卢克住在纽约。
So Luke is going to actually pick up Mr. Vincent or David Vincent and his wife at the airport.
所以卢克实际上会去机场接文森特先生或大卫文森特和他的妻子。
They have never met before.
他们以前从未见过面。
Never.
绝不。
OK.
好的。
So maybe they've communicated by email.
所以也许他们已经通过电子邮件进行了沟通。
They've discussed things before they've talked about details but this is their first in-person in-person
他们在谈论细节之前已经讨论过事情，但这是他们第一次面对面
meeting.
会议。
All right.
好的。
So that's the scene.
所以就是这样的场景。
That's what's going on.
这就是正在发生的事情。
And these are the characters that we will encounter in our dialogue.
这些是我们将在对话中遇到的角色。
Let us begin.
让我们开始吧。
David Vincent and his wife have landed and they've gone through to the baggage claim area to get their
大卫文森特和他的妻子已经降落，他们已经前往行李提取区取回他们的行李。
bags.
包。
And now they're going through the arrivals gate called the arrivals gate where people come out and often
现在他们正在通过被称为到达门的到达门，人们经常出来
there are many people in front of the arrivals gate waiting for family members or whatever if sometimes
到达门前有很多人在等待家人或其他什么，如果有时
if you're waiting for someone and you've never met them you might have a sign that says David and Lydia
如果你在等某人而你从未见过他们，你可能会有一个牌子，上面写着大卫和莉迪亚
Vincent maybe maybe not.
文森特也许不是。
If you've seen a picture of each other maybe it's not necessary.
如果你看过彼此的照片，也许没有必要。
But anyway here's Luke with his very poorly drawn head and crazy hair and sleepy eyes waiting for waiting
但无论如何，这是卢克，他的头画得很糟糕，头发疯狂，眼睛昏昏欲睡，等待着等待
for the Vincent's.
为文森特的。
And he sees who he thinks are Mr. and Mrs. Vincent.
他看到了他认为的文森特先生和夫人。
David and Lydia.
大卫和莉迪亚。
Vincent coming out of the arrivals gate and they're pulling their hair pulling their bags along they're
文森特从到达门出来，他们拉着头发，拉着他们的行李
pulling their luggage along.
拉着他们的行李。
Their luggage has wheels OK.
他们的行李有轮子还可以。
And there's a certain look right.
而且有一定的正确性。
Maybe they see the sign.
也许他们看到了标志。
If there's no sign maybe they just guessed that it's the other person.
如果没有任何迹象，他们可能只是猜测是另一个人。
But still you need to confirm.
但是你仍然需要确认。
So let's let's go through what we need to say when we need to confirm who this person is even though
所以让我们来看看当我们需要确认这个人是谁时我们需要说的话，即使
we're pretty sure.
我们很确定。
OK.
好的。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Luke might say so this is what Luke says.
路加可能会这么说，这就是路加所说的。
Excuse me are you Mr. Vincent.
对不起，你是文森特先生。
So Mr. Vincent sees Luke with the sign holding the sign and he walks up to the sign.
所以文森特先生看到卢克拿着牌子，他走到牌子前。
So clearly it is but you still have to confirm.
很明显，但你仍然需要确认。
Excuse me are you Mr. Vincent or just a question Mr. Vincent.
打扰一下，您是文森特先生还是只是文森特先生的问题。
Mr. Vincent.
文森特先生。
But it's very important to ask with a question tone if you say a question and you don't want to use
但是如果你说一个问题并且你不想用
are you.
你是。
It's very very important to make sure that you add a question tone so that your voice goes near and
确保添加问题语气以使您的声音接近并且非常重要，这一点非常重要
in it Mr. Vincent hungry ready sleepy.
文森特先生在里面饿了准备困了。
Ok.
好的。
Very important to have that question tone.
有这样的提问语气非常重要。
Ok then Mr. Vincent or David says yes please call me David please call me David.
好的，那么文森特先生或大卫说是的，请叫我大卫，请叫我大卫。
You must be Luke.
你一定是卢克。
Now this could be switched.
现在可以切换了。
Luke could say you must be David because David has walked up to the sign so that's OK to both of these
卢克可以说你一定是大卫，因为大卫已经走到标志牌前，所以这两个都可以
work.
工作。
You must be or with a question Tom.
你一定是或有一个问题汤姆。
Mr. Vincent look like that.
文森特先生长这样。
It could go either way.
它可以去任何一种方式。
All right.
好的。
Yes that's right.
是的，这是正确的。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
OK.
好的。
We can then add here if we want to we can say nice to finally meet you or nice to meet you and then
如果我们愿意，我们可以在此处添加我们可以说很高兴终于见到你或很高兴见到你然后
we could add here in person or we could say nice to finally meet you in person.
我们可以亲自在这里添加，或者我们可以说很高兴终于亲自见到你。
That means we've kind of met before but maybe we just met by email.
这意味着我们以前见过面，但也许我们只是通过电子邮件认识的。
So we didn't really meet.
所以我们并没有真正见面。
So we say in person that means face to face.
所以我们说面对面，意思是面对面。
So all of these can work.
所以所有这些都可以工作。
They can be flipped around but these are the phrases that are typically used here.
它们可以翻转，但这些是这里通常使用的短语。
But Mrs. Vincent is also here so it's very important that she become part of the conversation right
但文森特夫人也在这里，所以让她成为谈话的一部分非常重要
at the beginning because if she doesn't then she feels left out.
一开始是因为如果她不这样做，那么她会感到被冷落。
She feels uncomfortable and the situation will be very awkward.
她感到不舒服，情况会很尴尬。
So we want to avoid an awkward situation something that's awkward is where people who are there talking
所以我们想避免尴尬的情况，尴尬的地方是那里的人说话
to each other don't feel comfortable.
彼此都不舒服。
So if Luke doesn't recognize Mrs. Vincent or Lydia or maybe if David doesn't introduce his wife things
所以如果卢克不认识文森特夫人或莉迪亚，或者大卫不介绍他妻子的事情
will get awkward very soon even though Luke and David are the ones who know each other who have corresponded
很快就会尴尬，即使卢克和大卫是认识的人，也有通信过
maybe over the last few weeks.
也许在过去几周。
So let's look at the phrases we use for that.
因此，让我们看看我们为此使用的短语。
So let's get Lydia involved in the conversation.
所以让我们让莉迪亚参与对话。
Luke might say you must be Mrs. Vincent so you can do the same thing as before but with the person who
卢克可能会说你必须是文森特夫人，这样你才能像以前一样做同样的事情，但与
who is with Mr. Vincent.
谁和文森特先生在一起。
Then she has to confirm.
然后她必须确认。
I'm not going to write L because that would be confusing to have two l's but I am going to write M V.
我不会写 L，因为有两个 l 会让人困惑，但我会写 M V。
Mrs. Vincent Yes that's right.
文森特夫人 是的，没错。
Good to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Good day.
再会。
Pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
Aw it's a pleasure to meet you is more formal.
很高兴见到你更正式。
So be careful with that.
所以要小心。
You can say it here but you could also say Good to meet you and then you can use the name.
你可以在这里说，但你也可以说很高兴见到你，然后你可以使用这个名字。
Good to meet you Luke.
很高兴认识你，卢克。
Ok.
好的。
Or Mrs. Vincent could say this is an alternative one.
或者文森特夫人可以说这是另一种选择。
Yes I am.
我是。
You must be Mrs. Vincent.
你一定是文森特夫人。
Yes I am Mrs. Vincent.
是的，我是文森特夫人。
You can call me Lydia.
你可以叫我莉迪亚。
This is a good way to give people a more relaxed and informal feeling in basic conversation especially
这是在基本对话中给人们一种更轻松和非正式的感觉的好方法，尤其是
when you've just met somebody by by saying you can call me Blah blah blah.
当你刚刚遇到某人时说你可以叫我Blah blah blah。
It makes it feel a little informal.
这让人感觉有点不正式。
And that's good because then you can get to know them.
这很好，因为这样你就可以了解他们。
And if you're always saying Mr. Vincent this is Vincent then it feels a little bit a little bit stiff
如果你总是说文森特先生，这就是文斯nt 然后感觉有点僵硬
and not unfriendly but maybe too formal.
而且不是不友好，但可能太正式了。
Yes I am.
我是。
You can call me Lydia.
你可以叫我莉迪亚。
It's nice meeting you.
很高兴认识你。
Now we'll look at what Lou can say down here.
现在我们来看看娄在这里能说些什么。
But Lou could say of course likewise.
但娄当然也可以这样说。
It's nice to meet you too or you too sometimes Lou can say that as well.
很高兴见到你或者你也很高兴有时娄也可以这么说。
Now this is what David Vincent.
现在这就是大卫文森特。
Mr. Vincent says by the way whenever you want to suddenly change topics whatever it is you ought to
文森特先生顺便说一下，每当你想突然改变话题时，你应该怎么做
mention something else that's unrelated.
提及其他无关的事情。
Then we can use.
然后我们就可以使用了。
By the way.
顺便一提。
Now another way to do this is to say instead of by the way oh as though you forgot something.
现在另一种方法是说而不是顺便说一句哦，就好像你忘记了什么一样。
Oh yes.
哦是的。
Which might make Mrs. Vincent feel a little uncomfortable like he forgot his wife.
这可能会让文森特夫人感到有些不舒服，就像他忘记了他的妻子一样。
Right.
正确的。
So it's probably better here to use.
所以在这里使用可能会更好。
By the way by the way this is my wife Lydia.
顺便说一句，这是我的妻子莉迪亚。
And then Luke would say hi there.
然后卢克会在那里打招呼。
I've heard a lot about you from David.
我从大卫那里听说了很多关于你的事。
This is a common expression to use when you first met someone and you know the person who's introducing
这是您第一次见到某人并且您认识正在介绍的人时使用的常用表达
them whether it's a brother or a sister or a friend or a spouse.
无论是兄弟姐妹、朋友还是配偶。
In this case husband or wife.
在这种情况下，丈夫或妻子。
I've heard a lot about you means maybe David has told me about his wife.
我听说过很多关于你的事，这意味着大卫可能告诉过我他妻子的事。
In our e-mail exchanges makes the exchanges over the past few weeks.
在我们的电子邮件交流中进行了过去几周的交流。
So this is also very common.
所以这也是很常见的。
It's great to meet you both.
很高兴认识你们俩。
This one could be used if Luke hasn't already said Nice to meet you too David.
如果卢克还没有说很高兴见到你大卫，可以使用这个。
So David has said maybe you must be Luke.
所以大卫说也许你一定是卢克。
Yes that's right.
是的，这是正确的。
Oh this is my wife Lydia and oh it's it's nice to meet you both.
哦，这是我的妻子莉迪亚，哦，很高兴认识你们俩。
Luke could say so.
卢克可以这么说。
You can cover two people with one it's nice to meet you there.
你可以用一个覆盖两个人很高兴在那里见到你。
If if it hasn't already been said so that's possible.
如果还没有说过，那是可能的。
And then whenever you want to return what somebody says to you.
然后每当你想回复别人对你说的话。
You feel the same way you can say.
你的感觉和你说的一样。
Likewise likewise as I mentioned up here.
同样正如我在这里提到的。
So if I say tonight.
所以如果我今晚说。
Nice to meet you both.
很高兴认识你们俩。
They both say likewise.
他们都说同样的话。
Or maybe they say it's nice to meet you.
或者他们说很高兴认识你。
Maybe Lydia says it's very nice to meet you and I say Likewise likewise.
也许莉迪亚说认识你很高兴，我也说同样。
That means it's nice to meet you too.
这意味着很高兴认识你。
You can use likewise in a lot of other places you could say for example.
例如，您可以在许多其他地方使用同样的方法。
I really like your shoes.
我真的很喜欢你的鞋子。
Likewise.
同样地。
That means I like your shoes too.
这意味着我也喜欢你的鞋子。
So that's a way to say you too.
所以这也是一种说你的方式。
Sort of like playing ping pong.
有点像打乒乓球。
Hey.
嘿。
Yeah you too.
对，你也是。
Now this one is a little bit less formal.
现在这个有点不那么正式了。
This one might be too informal for this situation so kind of have to be careful with that but you can
对于这种情况，这可能过于非正式，因此必须小心，但您可以
say you to you too.
也对你说你。
You could say it's nice to meet you too.
你也可以说很高兴认识你。
All of these are OK all right.
这些都OK。
So now all people all three of us are in the conversation in the dialogue.
所以现在我们三个人都在对话中的对话。
Now we can continue and go to the question that we must ask if we've just picked someone up at the airport
现在我们可以继续讨论我们是否刚刚在机场接人的问题
and if you don't ask this question it's pretty much rude.
如果你不问这个问题，那就太粗鲁了。
So you have to ask this question which question you ask.
所以你要问这个问题是哪个问题哟你问。
Let's look at it now.
现在让我们来看看。
If you pick somebody up at the airport you have to ask them how the flight was.
如果您在机场接人，您必须询问他们的航班情况。
You could say How was your flight.
你可以说你的航班怎么样。
Or you could say How was the flight.
或者你可以说航班怎么样。
Both of those are OK but you really have to ask this question.
这两个都可以，但你真的必须问这个问题。
They're going to expect you to ask it.
他们会期待你问它。
It's really just a formality formality is something in usually a social situation not only.
这实际上只是一种形式 形式不仅是在通常的社交场合中的东西。
But something that kind of has to be done that's expected expected basically.
但是必须做一些基本上可以预料到的事情。
OK.
好的。
So how is your flight.
那你的航班怎么样。
This structure really is an important part of speaking English naturally and communicating with other
这种结构确实是自然地说英语和与他人交流的重要组成部分
native English speakers and in fact not.
以英语为母语的人，实际上不是。
Not every culture uses questions to get people to tell you what they think about something sometimes
并非每种文化都使用问题来让人们有时告诉你他们对某事的看法
different.
不同的。
Different cultures you just say your opinion right.
不同的文化你只是说你的意见是对的。
But in America particularly in American English you have to ask questions like How was your day.
但是在美国，尤其是在美国英语中，您必须问诸如您今天过得如何之类的问题。
How was the flight.
航班飞行如何。
How was work.
工作进展如何。
How's your family doing.
你的家人怎么样。
Whatever it is how's your job going.
不管你的工作进展如何。
This way we're able to get other people to share and then start a conversation.
通过这种方式，我们能够让其他人分享，然后开始对话。
That's very very important.
这是非常非常重要的。
So in this situation you really have to ask this.
所以在这种情况下你真的要问这个。
How was your flight.
你航班怎么样。
If you don't ask.
如果你不问。
Maybe they want to talk about the flight but they don't have a chance.
也许他们想谈谈飞行，但他们没有机会。
They feel like they have no opportunity to share their opinion.
他们觉得他们没有机会分享他们的意见。
Often native English speakers particularly in America need a question as a way to begin talking about
通常以英语为母语的人，尤其是在美国，需要一个问题作为开始谈论的方式
something and even if they want to say something they won't unless they get a question.
一些东西，即使他们想说些什么，除非他们有问题，否则他们不会说。
First part of the culture.
文化的第一部分。
OK it was fine but the in-flight meal could say the food.
好的，这很好，但机上的餐食可以说是食物。
We could also say the food the food was really not good.
我们也可以说食物的食物真的不好。
Really not good or not great.
真的不好或不好。
Or we could say terrible.
或者我们可以说可怕。
Or we could say fantastic if it was good.
或者，如果它很好，我们可以说太棒了。
But then we wouldn't say.
但是我们不会说。
But it was fine.
但这很好。
But the in-flight me it was really not good.
但是在飞行中我真的不太好。
The flight attendants.
空姐们。
Those are the people who work on the plane.
这些是在飞机上工作的人。
Basically waiters and waitresses called flight attendants.
基本上服务员和女服务员称为空姐。
That's male and female by the way male flight attendants.
顺便说一句，男性空乘人员是男性和女性。
Female flight attendants were all really friendly though.
不过，女空乘人员都很友善。
OK.
好的。
So this is a way to say but they were all very friendly.
所以这是一种说法，但他们都非常友好。
OK the flight attendants were all very friendly.
好的，空乘人员都非常友好。
That made it more comfortable.
这让它更舒服了。
What made it more comfortable.
是什么让它更舒服。
The friendly flight attendants.
友好的空姐。
OK so we have we have a bad thing the food we have a good thing the flight attendants.
好的，所以我们有我们有不好的食物我们有好的空姐。
OK.
好的。
Anyway anyway this is another way to make a final comment or sometimes go on to your last your last
无论如何，这是另一种发表最终评论的方式，或者有时继续你的最后一个你的最后一个
point.
观点。
If you're describing something or finish at least finish what you're saying.
如果您正在描述某事或完成至少要完成您所说的话。
Anyway we're glad to finally be here.
无论如何，我们很高兴终于来到这里。
So that suggests finally suggests it was a rather long rather long flight.
所以这表明最终表明这是一次相当长的飞行。
OK.
好的。
How was your flight.
你航班怎么样。
It was pretty good.
这是相当不错的。
Pretty good.
非常好。
Sometimes instead of using pretty good we say something like Well I can't complain.
有时，我们不使用相当好的东西，而是说像我不能抱怨的东西。
OK not bad.
不错不错。
So so really horrible really horrible.
太可怕了，太可怕了。
Oh really well.
哦，真的很好。
Why was it so horrible.
为什么会如此可怕。
Oh the whole flight.
哦，整个飞行。
We had terrible turbulence.
我们遇到了可怕的动荡。
This is when the plane shakes in the air.
这是飞机在空中摇晃的时候。
That's a horrible flight.
这是一次可怕的飞行。
If that's happening the whole time terrible turbulence.
如果这种情况一直在发生，那就是可怕的动荡。
OK.
好的。
Or we could say it was pretty good.
或者我们可以说它非常好。
But we're we are we're quite tired after our long trip and looking forward to a bit of rest.
但我们是我们是我们在长途旅行后很累，期待休息一下。
Now what that tells me if I'm picking them up is they want to go back to their hotel and maybe take
现在这告诉我，如果我要接他们，他们想回旅馆，也许会带走
a nap or just hang out for a little while and do nothing because they feel tired.
打个盹或者只是闲逛一会儿，因为他们感到疲倦而什么也不做。
Ok so I might want to say that next because I've recognized that's what they want because they're looking
好的，所以我接下来可能想说，因为我已经认识到这就是他们想要的，因为他们正在寻找
forward to a bit of rest.
稍作休息。
Now if this is an international flight and they've come from another country at least six or seven hours
现在，如果这是国际航班，而且他们从另一个国家来至少六七个小时
away then maybe we can talk about something called jet lag and jet lag is the idea of because you live
那么也许我们可以谈论一个叫做时差的东西，时差是因为你生活的想法
in another place far away you in your mind believe you feel that it is a different time.
在另一个遥远的地方，你在你的脑海里相信你觉得这是一个不同的时间。
So where you arrived it's 7:00 p.m. but maybe you feel it's only noon depending on where where you are
所以你到达的地方是晚上 7:00。但也许你觉得这只是中午，这取决于你在哪里
or maybe you feel instead of it being 7 p.m. maybe you feel at 7 a.m. This is called jet lag.
或者也许你觉得不是晚上 7 点。也许你在早上 7 点感觉到。这叫做时差。
I am so jet lagged I am so jet lagged.
我是如此时差 我是如此时差。
I really need to just sleep.
我真的需要睡觉了。
So jet lag is how we describe that feeling of our brain thinking it's a different time than it actually
所以时差是我们如何描述我们大脑的感觉，认为这是一个与实际不同的时间
is.
是。